

# CONTACT ME AT

Current Job Location :Bengaluru,
INDIA
Native :Bhopal INDIA

richadubey011@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/richadubey-4bbb0031

s live:richadubey011

+91-8446840238

# SKILLS SUMMARY

- •••• Mobile Application Testing
- •••• Web Application and ERP Testing
- •••• Test Planning and Strategies
- •••• Automation Framework
- ••• API Testing
- ••• Agile Methodologies & Cloud

# TOOLS <u>& TECHNO</u>LOGIES

- SELENIUM,APPIUM,UFT

  JAVA,MAVEN,INTELIJ,ECLIPSE
- ➤ POSTMAN, SOAP UI
- ➤ JIRA,TESTLINK,JENKINS,GIT
- BURP SUITE, ZAP PROXY, MOBSF

# RICHA DUBEY

# QA PROFESSIONAL

# **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

10+ years of Quality Assurance and Testing experience in Mobile Apps (Android and iOS) and Web applications testing using Manual and Automation techniques,

Worked on various domains like e-Commerce, OTT-Media & Entertainment, Insurance, Telecom, and Payments.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Consultant-QA/Test Lead

Capgemini(Bengaluru) | Nov 2020 - present

- Experience in Test planning, developing, and implementing test strategies to ensure software features meet business requirements.
- Involved in creating & maintaining Test cases/ Test Scripts.
- Managing and closely working with both On-shore and Offshore QA teams throughout the project, including BA, SM, and the development teams.
- Experience in Re-testing, Regression, Integration, and System testing, UAT.
- Experience in Agile methodologies, Waterfall in fast-paced environments.
- Responsible for creating clear & concise bug reports, with sufficient information for the developers to work on resolving the bug in a timely manner using JIRA.
- Experience in REST and SOAP API Testing, Created API automation test scripts using postman API and JavaScript using Newman command line collection runner.
- Experience in running SQL queries to do data validation.
- Experience with the UFT tool for generating test data, creating/maintaining scripts, and running a regression.
- Contributing to continuous improvements of test quality by undertaking reviews and recommending improvements.
- Experience in designing test repositories using Jira for tracking and maintaining test cases across cross-team and fetching Sprint reports.
- Experience in Salesforce, Azure integration testing.
- Experience in Pega/Guidewire Application Testing.
- Experience in the Insurance domain and a good understanding of the Claims life Cycle.

# CERTIFICATIONS

- Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate- CertiProf
- Cyber Security Foundation
  Professional Certificate-CertiProf
- Selenium Certified
- Appium Mobile Automation

# EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

- B.E Computer Science RGPV University 2010
- HSC
  Nalanda Public School 2006
- SSC
  Carmel Convent School 2004

# AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

- Spotlight -Recognized by Client and Capgemini-North America
- Awarded -SUPER SHEROES-Recognized by Capgemini for Outstanding performance and Contribution.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **QUALITY ANALYST**

CYS- CSS(Pune) | Nov 2019 - Nov 2020

- Working as Software Quality Analyst responsible for end to end testing life cycle and managing testing team.
- Experience in writing, developing, and executing test plans, test strategy, test scenarios, test cases.
- Experience in various detailed testing including running manual tests and automated scripts on portals.
- Experience in Agile methodologies (Kanban & Scrum).
- Working on the Web application, Mobile apps in various environments.
- Automating application Using Selenium with Java, TestNG,
   Maven, and generating reports in a timely manner.
- Good experience in testing REST API using Postman.
- Good experience in communicating business needs with internal and external teams.

# SOFT SKILLS

Quick Learner

Crtical Thinking

Creativity

Team Player

Pro Active

# LANGUAGES SKILLS

ENGLISH-Native/Bilingual

A HINDI-Native

GERMAN-Intermediate

MARATHI-Fluent

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Software Test Engineer

Jetsynthesys Private Ltd (Pune) | Feb 2014 - Aug 2019

- Experienced in analyzing user stories, use cases to develop a test plan, document maintain test cases, and other testing artifacts.
- Worked closely with other team members including developers, Managers, UI, product owners.
- Implement all levels of testing including System, Integration, and Regression.
- Experienced in developing test cases and compose automation scripts for web apps and mobile apps.
- Experienced with postman API testing in multiple projects.
- Good experience with Jira and Confluence.
- Identified track software defects, inconsistencies, and the ability to document and troubleshoot errors.
- Experienced with Security testing of Web apps using Kali Linux, Burp Suite, and Zap proxy, Mob-SF.
- Experienced with video streaming, OTT Platform like Apple TV, Android TV.
- Experienced in the AWS device farm, Browser stack to test the app on multiple devices and os compatibility.
- Worked on deployed Apps and streams using Amazon S3, Amazon VPC, Lambda.
- Experienced with database testing to validate the test results or create test data to execute results.
- Experienced in testing VAS, payment apps, Loan, and Entertainment Streaming apps.
- Experienced with automation tools like Selenium with Java, Maven, TestNG, Extent Reports.
- Experience with Data-driven and involved in BDD Framework.
- Experience with Appium to Automate Mobile applications.
- Well versed with CI/CD environments.

# Software Test Engineer

Vyaas Technologies (Pune) | Jun 2012 - Feb 2014

- Experienced in analyzing Business, Functional, Technical, and UI (User Interface) requirements of the projects.
- Identified risks and provide mitigation plans.
- Execution of test cases, documenting the results and defects, and following up on issues.
- Involved in end to end ERP Testing.
- Responsible for overall adherence to QA test Protocols and processes.